我听过的
I know that one.
外公录音的时候我也在
I was at the studio when grandfather recorded it.
想妈妈了?
Been thinking about your mom?
妈妈, 一切, 我一生
Mama,everything,my whole life.
是个彻头彻尾的谎言
It was all a lie.
我从来不知道你
I never knew you.
从不知道你是我爸爸
I never knew you were my dad.
一切会好起来的, Leona
Your life's going to be okay,leona.
你是一个好孩子, 你振作起来
You're a good kid.You got it together.
这八个月你坚持住了, 全靠自己
Survived the last eight months.On your own.
你不是你外公
You're not your grandfather.
也不是你妈妈
Or your mom.
你不会和他们犯同样的错
You're not going to make,the same mistakes they did.
我很骄傲我是你的父亲
I'm proud that i'm your father.
能有这个机会我好高兴
I'm glad I'm getting this chance.
要来块小甜饼吗, 亲爱的?
ready for a cookie,darling?
快跑! 离开这儿!
We gotta go!Get out of here!
Leona!
您拨通了一个无法接通的号码,且已经作废
You've reached a number that has been,disconnected and is no longer in service.
如果您是无意中听到这通电话留言,请听我的号令挂断
If you feel you've reached this,recording in error,go with it,hang up.
数到三. 一, 二--
On three.One,two--
House, 接电话. 我知道你在休假
House,pick up.I know it's your day off.
无疑你有许多激动人心的计划
And you've no doubt got lots of exciting plans,
但是这有个病例
but I've got a case.
16岁女孩呈心原性休克
16-year-old girl presenting,with cardiogenic shock.
却没有心脏病发作
But no heart attack.
她的心脏看起来没问题,急救中心做了全套的心脏检查
her heart looks fine.E.R.,Did a full cardiac work-up.
毒物筛检阴性, 血液检测无感染
Tox screen's clean,blood shows no infection.
全在首页上. 我是个好读者
All on the top page.I'm a real good reader.
个人关系栏空着, 说明有隐情
Personal chart hand-off means,there's something else.
希望不是跟我有关
I'm hoping it's not personal.
带女孩来的那个人说他认识你
The guy who brought the girl,in says he knows you.
我还以为我见过你所有的朋友呢
I thought I'd met all your friend.
能不能再看看这些
I was also wondering if you could,take a look at these.
唔, 如果你有时间的话. 不急
um,when you have a chance.No hurry.
几份医学纪录, 其中一人有癌症风险
It's just a couple of medical histories,,one with a minor cancer concern.
没问题
No problem.
G-老兄!
G-man!
你以为我会抱你, 是不是?
You thought I was gonna do it,didn't you?
我认识你吗?
Do I know you?
得了吧你, 是我. Crandall
Come on,it's me.Crandall.
没印象...
Doesn't ring a bell.
伙计, 我不能相信你竟然忘记--
Man,I can't believe you've forgotten--
难道你是 Dylan Crandall,那个什么都信的家伙
unless you mean dylan crandall,,the man who'll believe anything.
瞧, 我刚刚使你相信我--
See,I just made you believe that I--
你一点没变
you haven't changed.
关于你的腿的事听说了
Heard about your leg.
嗯, 玩扭扭乐的时候扯到脚筋,走走就好了
Yeah,pulled a hamstring playing twister.,Just gonna walk it off.
那个女孩是谁?
So who's the girl?
Jesse Baker 的外孙女
Jesse baker's granddaughter.
你总是说, 宁愿舍掉右手,只要能像他一样弹奏
You always said you'd give your,right hand to play like him.
没有, 我是说,愿用我的右手换他的左手
No,I said I'd give my right,hand to have his left.
她怎么和你在一块?
Why is she with you?
她在 卡特琳娜飓风来袭时,失去了妈妈, 她的家, 一切
She lost her mom in katrina.,Her home,everything.
我是她父亲
And I'm her father.
唔. 是呀, 看起来可真像你,一样的黑人鬈曲发型
Hmm.Yeah,she looks just like you.,Got the same 'fro.
我写了一本关于Baker的书,和他相处了一段, 还有她女儿
I wrote a book about baker.,Hung out with him.And his daughter.
婴儿是这样制造的
That is how babies are made.
我一直不知道. 她也不知道
I never knew.She never knew.
她妈妈骗了我们16年
Her mom lied for 16 years.
难以置信
That's unbelievable.
是啊
Yeah.
说真的, 我不信
No,seriously.I don't believe it.
她妈妈因我的书大怒,我把他们贬得一无是处
Her mom was pissed at me about my book.,I trashed her and her dad.
她不再和我说话,显然她也不会告诉Leona--
She wouldn't talk to me.,Obviously she's not gonna tell leona that--
你是个笨蛋. 一直都是
you're a sucker.You always were.
那是不是意味着你不会救她?
Does that mean you're not going to help her?
为什么我不会?
Why wouldn't I?
她又没有诓骗我
She's not scamming me.
急性心肌梗塞?
acute myocardial infarction?
急救中心说不是的. 再查一次
E.R. Said no.Retest.
预激综合征?(心房或心室某一部分提前激动)
Wolff-parkinson-white syndrome?
急诊否定了. 再查,看看那该死的病历
E.R. Said no.Retest.And read the damn file.
你刚给我们
You just gave them to us.
- 心电图显示δ波,- 全都不是
Delta wave on the ekg--it's all a no.
关于她心脏的一切指数都很健康
Everything about her heart is healthy.
她是卡特琳娜飓风的受害者
She's a katrina victim.
她可比 Crandall 要幸运,他是飓风受害者的受骗者
She's better than crandall.,He's a katrina victim victim.
我不认为她想博得你的同情
I don't think she was expecting yo sympathy.
我想她的关键点是,新奥尔良就像一个第三世界国家
I think her point was,,new orleans was a third-world country.
街上到处都是毒素, 霉菌, 污水
Toxins,molds,sewage in the streets.
也许她的心脏就像我的摩托车?
What if her heart is like my bike?
我骑的时候, 废铜烂铁,一带到技师那里, 运转自如
Runs like crap when I'm by myself,,but if I take it to the mechanic,it runs great.
心律不齐. 一次性的?
an arrhythmia.One-time event?
那我们怎么办?给她接上心脏监视器, 干等着
What are we going to do,,keep her in a room on a cardiac monitor until
直到另一次的心律不齐?那可能需要几星期, 甚至几个月
she has another arrhythmia?That could be weeks,months.
放松点,我知道午饭后她就要来一次
Relax.I happen to know,she's going to have one right after lunch.
机会难得
We are golden.
你不能给48小时前心脏差点衰竭的,病人再引导一次心律不齐
You can't induce an arrhythmia on someone,whose heart nearly gave out 48 hours ago.
你当然可以
Sure you can.
技术活, 把很酷的细电线插入病人的心脏
It's kind of technical,you stick all,these cool little wires inside r somehow.
我是说不该这么做
I mean you shouldn'T.
噢, 是啊, 让病情不可控制地发作,会道德得多
Oh,right,because it would be much more ethical,to let it happen in an uncontrolled setting.
午饭时, 邻桌总会有一队心脏病专家,这里是新泽西州
There's always a team of cardiologists,having lunch at the next table.This is jersey.
她未成年. 需要监护人同意
She's a minor.She's going to need consent.
我去和他谈谈
I'll go talk to him.
噢, 计划真是太妙了
Oh,that's an excellent plan.
给他一张表格, 告诉他那是,错误而危险的
Give him the form and tell him,it's wrong and dangerous.
我能搞定一份简单的同意书
I can handle a simple consent form.
好
Okay.
我当 Crandall
I'll be crandall.
Cameron 医生!
Dr. Cameron!
- House, 依你所说, 这人会信赖,- 你参演吗?
House,from what you say,,this guy will trust--are you in this scene?
开始
Go.
我得和你谈谈,打算对 Leona 实施的方案
I need to talk to you about a,procedure we'd like to do on leona.
打算?
Like to do?
对你来说很有趣吗?
Is this fun for you?
他不是你. 他不会嘲笑我--
He's not you.He's not going to mock me--
扮演好角色
stay in character.
我好怕. 抱住我
I'm so scared.Hold me.
为了查出哪个回路不起作用
In order to figure out which,circuit is misfiring,
得绘出心脏的每个心电活动
we need to map all the electrical,activity in her heart.
手放在圣经上发誓,如果是你的孩子, 也会这么做
Swear to me on the bible,you'd do this if it was your kid.
再见
Good-bye.
为了绘出她的心电通路
To map the electrical,pathways in her heart,
对每个回路都给电,一次一个, 直到有一个失败
we send electricity through each,,one at a time,until one fails.
听起来很危险
That sounds dangerous.
这是我准备接受的风险
It's a risk i am prepared to take.
如果她心电有问题,更多的电流不会摧毁整个系统吗?
If she's got an electrical problem,couldn't,more electricity blow her whole system?
唔, 谁一直在看 "Bill Nye, 那个,搞科学的家伙" (儿童科普节目)
Well,look who's been watching,bill nye the science guy.
测试非常安全. 每天都做
Test is perfectly safe.We do it every day.
你相信了我所说的
And you believe me.
我不该做那个测试吗?
I shouldn't do the test?
其实极其危险
It's crazy dangerous.
把该死的表格签了吧
Just sign the damn form.
我没有哭. 我能对付
I'm not crying.I can handle this.
那就擤擤鼻涕吧
Then blow your nose.
我得搞点DNA
I need dna from somewhere.
你不是要做亲子鉴定吧
You're not running a paternity test.
她会和你待在一起,直到拿到你的银行帐户
She's gonna stay around just,long enough to get your bank account,
信用卡号码,然后就随她的下个老爸消失
your credit card numbers,then she's,going to be off with her next daddy.
想想她都经历了什么,你怎么能猜测--
With what she's been through,,why would you assume--
就是因为她经历了那些
because of what she's been through.
因为那是你默认的姿态,一直都是
Because that's your default position.,Always has been.
是因为她还活着
Because she's still alive.
被瘾君子养大, 睡大街的孩子,不太可能还保持善良
Raised by a junkie,living on the streets,,that tends to kick the sweetness out of you.
我以为你已经没那么愤世
I figured you'd have mellowed.
因为你是个白痴
Because you're an idiot.
如果我让你做亲子鉴定,意味着我不信任她
If I let you do the test,,it means I don't trust her.
不, 意味着我不信任她
No,it means I don't trust her.
- 100, 99, 98 ...,- 她失去意识了
100,99,98...she's out.
心律正常. 插入第一根导管
heart rhythm's normal.,Insert the first catheter.
进去了
I'm in.
所有的心律仍然正常
all heart rhythms still normal.
还没开始放电
haven't zapped her yet.
发送第一个电脉冲
send the first electrical pulse.
窦结节正常
Sinoatrial node is normal.
下一个
Next.
- 我看到室上性心动过速了,- 切断电流
I've got supraventricular tachycardia.,--Stop the current.
她产生幻觉了吗?
Is she hallucinating?
立即静脉推注12.5单位腺苷
I.V. Push stat,12.5 adenosine.
她不行了, 血压垂直下降
She's crashing.B.P.'S plummeting.
Foreman, 她现在有幻觉吗?
Foreman,is she hallucinating?
没有, 正常脑波
No,normal waves.
房室结不是问题所在
The av node is not the bad pathway.
仅仅心脏病发作
All that was was a heart attack.
重新开始, 找出真正的病因
Reset her so we can find the real problem.
- 充电,- 复位
Charging.--Clear.
正常心律
normal rhythm.
Chase. 给右心房上部来一次
Chase.High right atrium,please.
上次发作之后, 她的心脏非常脆弱,造成心动过速的可能性--
Her heart's fragile after that,last attack.Chances of tachycardia--
我允许你在医疗疏忽审查中,谴责Foreman
you have my permission to blame,foreman at any negligence trial.
发送电脉冲
send the electrical pulse.
就是那个. 她开始产生幻觉
That's the one.She's hallucinating.
靠近冠状窦
It's near the coronary sinus.
把它冰冻
Freeze it.
坏死的心肌被分离, 冰刀治疗完毕
damaged heart muscle gone.,Cryoblation complete.
脑电图恢复正常, 没有幻觉
the eeg's back to normal.,No hallucinations.
明天早饭前她就好了
She'll be fine by breakfast.
有趣的读物
Interesting reading.
那是我最中意的两位精子捐赠者
Those are my top two choices for sperm donors.
我需要你遗传学的医学建议
I wanted your medical opinion on genetics.
他们都是失败者
They're losers.
呃, 医学上的, 还是--
Uh,medically,or--
1284号捐赠者喜欢跳方块舞
donor 1284 likes square dancing.
没人喜欢跳方块舞
No one likes square dancing.
613号玩了5分钟医学,就称自己为 "医疗者"
613's been practicing medicine for,five minutes.Calls himself a "healer."
喜欢莫扎特
Loves mozart.
我又不是和他们跳舞,我寻找的是健康的精子
I'm not going dancing with them,,I'm looking for healthy sperm.
他四位祖父母都活着
He got four living grandparents.
他们是谁, 干什么的--,一点都不重要吗?
Who they are,what they do--that,doesn't matter?
我倾向于613号
I'm leaning towards 613.
噢, 那当然了, 追随犹太数字,(613在犹太人文化中经常出现)
Oh,sure,go with the jewish number.
1284号有个堂姐被测出Brca1基因阳性,(此基因突变易引起乳腺癌及卵巢癌)
1284 has a cousin that tested,positive for the brca1 gene.
但他母亲是阴性的,你的宝宝也会是阴性
But his mother was negative,,which means so's your baby.
- 还有 - 父方的地中海-荷兰贫血因子?那不是问题
What about the--mediterranean-dutch,factor on the dad's side?It's not a problem,
因为他老爸的妈不携带地中海贫血基因
because his dad's mom didn't,carry the thalassemia gene.
更大的问题是他的,性情古怪和装腔作势基因
The bigger issue is the jerk and poser genes.
- 喜欢莫扎特的谎言,- 人们不能喜欢古典乐?
This mozart lie--people can't,like classical music?
你正在设计一个孩子--,一个注定失败的孩子
You're designing a kid--a loser kid.
我都预见他在课间被揍了
He's already getting pummeled at recess.
够了. 醒醒吧
Here.Knock yourself out.
去找个精子, 能打败613号的孩子
Go find sperm that can beat up 613's kids.
谢谢你帮忙
And thanks for your help.
自命不凡会遗传的
Pretentiousness is hereditary.
只是还未发现确定基因罢了
Just 'cause they haven't found the gene yet...
能给我点水喝吗?
could I have some water,please?
有人么? 我要喝点水
Hello?I just need some water.
有人在吗?
Is anyone there?
妈妈?
Mama?
不!
No!
再次产生幻觉说明心脏没有医好,也许遗漏了什么
a second hallucination means we didn't,fix her heart.Maybe we missed something.
她心脏完好, 如果她产生幻觉,不是心脏的原因
Her heart's fine.If she hallucinated,,it wasn't caused by her heart.
如果? 尖叫, 挣扎在水中? 这是幻觉
if?The screaming,the floundering?It was a hallucination.
要是这不是幻觉呢?
What if it wasn't a hallucination?
- 检查包括了,- 还没说完
We covered--not finished.
如果是非典型癫症呢?
What if it was an atypical seizure?
癫症? 她看见妈妈. 她妈妈死了,据此, 是幻觉
seizure?She saw her mother.Mother's dead.,Ergo,hallucination.
谁能解释下这?
Anyone want to explain that?
他腿疼. 走动能转移注意力
His leg hurts.Walking takes,his mind off of it.
镜头闪回
A flashback.
飓风带来狂风暴雨, 创伤后压力综合症
All that wind and rain from the hurricane.,Post-traumatic stress syndrome.
你为什么如此倾向她不是幻觉?
Why are you so bent on her not,having a hallucination?
如果她是幻觉
If she did have a hallucination,
那我们预见, 发现并修复的,心脏问题就是天大的巧合了
then the heart problem that we predicted,found,,and fixed was just a gigantic coincidence.
- 他的腿不是一直疼么?- 越来越糟了
His leg always hurts.--It's getting worse.
如果她的心脏不是巧合
What if the heart isn't a coincidence,
也不是造成幻觉的原因
and isn't what caused the hallucination?
心律不齐很疼
Arrhythmia hurts.
也许她的幻觉是疼痛造成的?
What if her hallucination was caused by pain?
也许她得了病
What if she has a disease
疼痛被转译成古怪的生理反应,好比幻觉?
that translates pain into a bizarre,physiological response,like a hallucination?
她有自身免疫性疾病,要做C-反应蛋白, 类风湿因子--
She has an autoimmune disease.,She needs a crp,a rheumatoid factor--
我能在5分钟里确诊一个自身免疫性疾病,做正电子发射层扫描 (pet scan)
I can prove an autoimmune disease,in five minutes.She needs a pet scan.
自身免疫性疾病没这么快查出来
You can't test for autoimmune in--
我来证明她的幻觉,是对于疼痛的连贯反映
I'm proving that her hallucinations,are a consistent response to pain,
就能证明她得了自身免疫性疾病
which proves that she has an autoimmune disease.
你怎么来检测对于疼痛的反应？
How do you test someone's response to pain?
简单. 弄疼她
Easy.Hurt them.
一点都不疼的
It's not going to hurt at all.
但得保证你不移动
But we just need to make sure you don't move.
我不动
I won'T.
好, 给我手臂
Okay,give me your arm.
要检查你肌肉的反应
I need to check your muscle responses.
好, 翻过来, 手掌朝上
Okay,turn it over.Palm upward.
还好么?
Everything okay?
是的
Yeah.
- 哇!,- 这是干什么?
Ow!--What the hell was that?
诊断检查
diagnostic test.
大脑皮层灰质应答如常, 没有幻觉
Cerebral cortex responded normally.,She's not hallucinating.
你知道他不是你父亲, 是吗?
You know he's not your father,don't you?
他是我父亲. 妈妈告诉我的
He's my dad.Mama told me.
对不起, 我不想伤害你的
I'm sorry,I didn't mean to hurt you.
House, 别碰她
House,leave her alone.
说吧, 你我都清楚, 这是诈骗
Come on,we both know it's a hustle.
墙壁合起来了？
Are the walls closing in?
没有. 你为什么这么做?
No.Why are you doing this?
蜘蛛从我鼻孔里爬出来?
Spiders coming out of my nose?
让我出去
Let me out.
House, 检查结束. 背侧前额皮层--
House,the test is over.,Dorso-lateral prefrontal cortex--
- 把手给我,- 不!
give me your hand.--No!
把手给我
Give me your hand.
放过他吧
Forget him.
他可不是完美的猎物,他曾经是完美猎物
He's not the perfect mark because,he was the perfect mark.
在你之前, 早有人跃跃欲试
Plenty of people got there before you.
他已经被用尽榨干了
He's used up.Tainted.Pumped dry.
产生幻觉了
she's hallucinating.
她失去了一切. 还被拗断手指, 再创新低
she's lost everything.And you're,breaking fingers.A new low.
为了诊断, 她需要疼痛,我也想弄疼她, 双赢
Diagnoically,she needed to be hurt.,I wanted to hurt her.Win-win.
我没有预见到触发幻觉的阈值
What I didn't consider was a,threshold to trigger the hallucinations.
不然的话, 我在刺她两下之前就拗手指了,刚才太残忍了
Otherwise,I'd have done the finger-bending first,instead of stabbing her twice.That was cruel.
如果她的自身免疫性病已濒晚期,寻常的治疗无济于事
If her autoimmune disease is this advanced,,usual treatment's not going to help.
都不知道她得了那一种自身免疫性疾病
We don't even know which,autoimmune disease she has.
也许是肌无力综合症, 也许是G型甲亢--
Could be lambert-eaton,could be graves--
好主意, 一次屠杀殆尽
good point.Let's kill them all at once.
唯一的办法是更换整个免疫系统
the only way to do that is to,replace her entire immune system.
好主意, 就这么干
Good point.Let's do that.
骨髓移植需要精确的匹配
Bone marrow transplant requires an exact match.
Leona 没有同胞姐弟
Leona has no siblings.
好主意
Good point.
她孤苦无依. 整个世界举目无亲
She's all alone,poor thing.,No one in the whole,wide world.
我说过要校音的, 这个乐器校过了?
I asked for this tuned.,Did you get this instrument tuned?
要是我女儿需要骨髓,你为什么查骨髓注册库?
If my daughter needs bone marrow,why are,you looking in a bone marrow registry?
因为骨髓在那里保存
Because that's where they keep the bone marrow.
我是她爸爸
I'm her father.
一个无条件相信一切的人,怎么能当传记作家
How does somebody who believes absolutely,anything become a nonfiction writer?
检查我的骨髓
Test my bone marrow.
故事会这样结束
Here's how this is going to end.
一天, 你坐在电脑前, 写一本音乐小书
One day,you'll be sitting at your computer,,writing one of your little music books,
你女儿回家, 带来愤怒的大个子警察,把你扔进监狱
and your daughter will come home with a big,,angry policemanwho'll throw you in jail
因为, "爸爸碰了我小洞洞."
because,"daddy touched my poozle."
查我吧
Test me.
很乐意
Happy to.
只是我的骨髓. 我不授权亲子鉴定
Just my marrow.,I'm not authorizing a paternity test.
你害怕真相?
You're that afraid of the truth?
我知道真相
I know the truth.
小骚妖精的真相是,她需要张公车票回家看生病的祖母
Easy lay fay's truth was that she needed,a bus ticket home to see her sick grandma.
你给了她 100 块钱
You gave her 100 bucks.
她去买了大麻
She bought weed.
因为是我告诉她,你肯定会因为病奶奶的故事上当
I know,because I told her you'd,go for the sick grandma story.
如果我们的友情对你还有意义--
If our friendship means anything to you--
哦, 你真的了解我吗?
oh,come on.Do you know me at all?
要是你做了亲子鉴定. 两个结果,要么你对, 要么我对
If you do the test,one of two things happens.,Either you're right or I'm right.
你对, 我很悲惨
If you're right,I'll be miserable.
我对, 我会恨自己. 因为我不信任她,两者, 我皆输
And if I'm right,I'll hate myself,'cause I didn't trust her.Either way,I lose.
不痒, 也不突起
They don't itch.Not raised.
他打过预防针了
He's had his mmr.
学校里没人生病, 爸爸带他去露营
No one's sick at school.,His father took him camping.
我们捉到两只蜘蛛
We caught two spiders.
你没告诉我蜘蛛的事
You didn't tell me about the spiders.
你有新的睡椅?
Did you get a new couch?
- 你觉得是不是什么毒素?- 什么颜色?
Do you think there might,be some sort of toxin?--What color is it?
红的
Red.
你洗完澡是不是趴着看卡通?
Is that where you watch your,cartoons after you take your bath?
有时候睡着了?
Fall asleep sometimes?
- 是的,- 保佑你
Yes.--Bless you.
需要你, 现在
Need you.Now.
是的, 夫人
Yes,mistress.
我开张处方, 一块这个, 弄湿了用
I'll write you a prescription for,one of these.Just wet and apply.
你没告诉任何人, 我想干什么?
You didn't tell anyone else what I'm doing?
一个都没有
Not a soul.
Wilson?
Cameron, 也许你跟她提过
Cameron,maybe you mentioned it to her.
不, 我是绝好的守密者
No,I'm a really good secret-keeper.
从没告诉任何人, wilson 尿床
I never told anybody that wilson wets his bed.
哦, 你套我的话
Oh,you tricked me.
体外受精的方法包括,一天两次注射尿促性素
Part of the protocol for in vitro fertilization,is twice-daily injections of menotropins.
我自己干不了
I can't do it myself.
转过身
Turn around.
对我弯下身不说点怪话?
No clever comments about bending over?
除非你想让我说
Not unless you want me to.
只是不太习惯专业操守的house
I'm just not used to house the professional.
我在想你妈妈长得什么样
I was just thinking about what,your mother looked like.
因为你爸爸明显因为繁衍需要选择她
Since your father obviously chose,her for breeding purposes--
闭嘴
shut up.
自然选择毫无道理
Natural selection sucks.
我们挑选配偶基于胸部的大小, 所开的车
We pick our mates based on breast size,,cars they drive.
对已婚夫妻的解剖发现,这些和胰腺的大小呈相关
They did autopsies on married couples.,Found a correlation in pancreas size.
本能驱使我们按照愚蠢的理由选择,你本可以有聪明的选择
We're hard-wired to pick for stupid reasons.,You have the chance to pick for smart reasons.
我想德国人有相近的理论, 大概在60年前
I think the germans had a similar,theory about 60 years ago.
我不是在鼓吹种族灭绝, 只是说
I'm not advocating wiping out entire races.,I'm just saying,
你不该随随便便和某个盛精子的塑料杯交配
you don't want to mate with,the first plastic cup that buys you a drink.
擦得差不多了吧
I'm pretty sure you got that.
细菌很鬼祟
Microbes can be sneaky.
谢谢
Thanks.
一天两次, 会很好玩
Twice a day.This is going to be fun.
我来好了
I got it.
你怎么会跟他成了朋友?
So why were you friends with this guy?
我们20岁时, 他有一辆车
We were 20 years old.He had a car.
他要是个女人, 我都可能娶他
If he'd been a woman,I would have married him.
- 他匹配吗?- 不
- Is he a match?- No.
说谎的女孩子走运了,在骨髓库里发现一例匹配
Lying girl lucked out.We found,one in the registry.
他是不是爸爸？
Is he the dad?
- 我认为不是,- 你没有做亲子鉴定？
- I don't think so.,- You didn't run the test?
说过我不会做
Said I wouldn'T.
好, 要么你说谎, 要么...
Okay.So either you lied,or he has...
他唤起了你的良知?
pictures of you being nice.
停止放射
Stop the radiation.
这究竟是什么?
What the hell is that?
不知道
I have no idea.
对黑色渗出物的实验结果, 难以置信
Lab results on the black ooze.,You're not gonna believe it.
她从嘴里拉便便
She pooped out of her mouth.
样本包含粪便, 经消化后的血液,你怎么猜到的?
The sample contains stool,and digested blood.How did you guess?
因为它是慢慢渗出的
Because it oozed.
如果来自胃, 应该喷溅出
If it was in her stomach,it would have sprayed.
如果在肺里, 她该呛得咳嗽,这慢慢渗出, 如同受挤压, 反向蠕动
If it was in her lungs,she would have coughed.,This oozed,as in squeezed,as in reverse peristalsis.
有谁饿了吗? 墨西哥菜外卖?
Who's hungry?Mexican takeout?
消化后血液在她小肠里的话,她应该有内出血
In order for digested blood to be in her,intestines,she had to have internal bleeding.
不论肠道有什么东西反涌, 下面必定梗阻了
Order for whatever was in her intestines,to come back up,there had to be a blockage.
肝功能衰竭. 没有使血液凝结的蛋白质,因此渗进她的胃, 搞一团糟
liver failure.There'd be no proteins to clot the blood,,so it'd leak into her stomach,mess up her intestines.
说明, 啊, 错了,没有一种自体免疫病能在2小时内关闭器官
Which means,oops,we were wrong.Because no,autoimmune disease shuts down an organ in two hours.
要做一个肝脏活组织检查,找出真正问题所在
We need to do a liver biopsy,,find out what the real problem is.
嘿. 要跟你谈一下
Hey.Need to talk to you.
好消息是, 她没有自身免疫的情形
The good news is,she doesn't,have an autoimmune condition,
所以她不需要骨髓移植, 放射也及时停止
so she doesn't need a bone marrow transplant,,and we were able to stop the irradiation in time.
坏消息是, 她嘴里排便
Bad news,she has potty mouth.
肝脏衰竭, 使得消化系统颠倒
Her liver is failing,which has made,her digestive system go in reverse.
比听上去要严重得多
It's actually much worse than it sounds.
需要做肝脏活组织检查
We need to do a liver biopsy.
我不知会怎么样, 当把针插入她的肝脏
I don't know what's going to happen,when we stick a needle into her liver.
她可能会当场死亡
She could die right then and there.
你得告诉我该怎么做
You need to tell me what to do.
对此没有内部消息
No inside information on thione.
Crandall, 三天前, 你还不认识这女孩
Crandall,three days ago,,you didn't even know this girl.
她可能遭遇车祸, 你不会因此失眠
If she'd been hit by a bus,,you wouldn't lose a moment's sleep.
医院里满是同样困扰重重,同样和你没有血缘的人
There are people all over this hospital in just,as much trouble,and just as not related to you.
你说我不应该在乎?
You telling me i shouldn't care?
为她死时, 做好心理准备?
Prepping me to handle it for when she dies?
棕色, 结块的
It's brown,it's lumpy.
我要吐一桌子了
I'm going to heave all over my desk.
鸡汁?
Chicken mol?
含21种草本和香料
21 herbs and spices.
我觉得很安慰
I find it very comforting,
你在保护一个多年未见的人
you defending a man you haven't seen in years.
知道我的朋友, 无论如何,他都会是我的战士, 我的守护者
To know my friend,no matter what,,will always be my champion.My protector.
我不是在保护他, 是在打击她
I'm not protecting him,I'm smacking her.
谦逊的真心英雄
The modesty of a true hero.
再逼我, 我就弄死她,你就不能嘲弄我了
Push me and I'll let her die,,just so you'll stop annoying me.
我的理论是, 你妒嫉了
Here's my theory.You're jealous.
他成熟了, 在担负责任,而你在情感上, 停留在了17岁
He's maturing,he's accepting responsibility,,you're emotionally stuck at 17.
他在制造责任, 他不是成熟了
He's manufacturing responsibility,,he's not maturing.
他一点都没有变
He hasn't changed at all.
那么, 你为什么在乎?
So then,why do you care?
看到的黑色渗出物?
That black ooze we saw?
是肠子的排泄物
That was a bowel movement.
从她嘴里出来
Out of her mouth.
你想让我恶心, 来结束谈话?
You're trying to end,this conversation by grossing me out?
我是肿瘤学家,我一半的病人皮肤腐败
I'm an oncologist.,Half my patients have their skin sloughing off.
你为何担心这个男人?
Why are you so worried about this guy?
他和女朋友曾有一段关系紧张
He was having a rough time with his girlfriend.
他陷在爱里, 他总是爱着
He was in love.He was always in love.
想要娶她, 我觉得她不可靠
Wanted to marry her.I thought she was flaky.
她模棱两可
She was sending mixed signals.
所以你给他出主意, 导致他被甩?
So you gave him advice and she dumped him.
不, 我说我去和她谈谈
No,I told him that i would talk to her.
可你搞砸了
And you blew it?
技术上讲... (反过来),( "blew" 搞砸, 口交, 双关)
Technically...
我那是帮他, 她是个蠢女人
I was doing him a favor.She was nuts.
停止活组织检查
Stop the biopsy.
马上就到肝脏了
I'm right at her liver.
是House, 他说停止
It's house.He says stop.
听听这个
Check it out.
千万别告诉我停止切片检查,是为了播放乐曲
Please tell me you didn't stop,the biopsy to play us some tunes.
左手, 多么微妙, 多么精巧
The left hand.It's very subtle.,Very delicate.
那女孩快死了
This girl is dying.
做那个明显无用的切片检查,死得更快, 仔细听
Be dying a lot faster if I let you do,that obviously unnecessary biopsy.Now listen.
我说了让人来调一下音, 调了没有?
I asked for this tuned.,Did you get this tuned?
我的天, 外公是个狂怒的醉鬼,不说我还真不知道
My god,grandpa was an angry drunk.,If only we'd known.
伟大的艺术家是这样修炼的
Here's how to become a great artist.
首先, 生活凄惨
First,get miserable.
凄惨可以使你成为伟大的艺术家
Misery drives you to become a great artist,
但艺术无法改善凄惨, 逼你吸毒
but the art does nothing for your misery,,which drives you to drugs,
让你变成差劲的艺术家,但这一段并不差劲
which makes you a lousy artist.,And this is not lousy.
你说他没有吸毒?
You saying he didn't do drugs?
演奏这段时没有
Not when he played this.
有什么扭曲了他的性格
Something was screwing with his personality.
毒品和酒不能起到这个作用?
Yeah,drugs and alcohol don't do that?
他说走调的那个音并没有走调
And that note that he says is out of tune,,it's not.
这说明有东西同时扭曲了他的听觉
Which means that something is screwing,with his aural perception too.
结合这些, 再加上导致他死亡的肝病,有什么结论?
Now,what happens when you add all of that to,the liver disease which he supposedly died of?
铁元素过量, 他可能患有血色病,(影响铁的新陈代谢) 遗传性疾病
Too much iron.He could have had hemochromatosis.,That's genetic.
难道 Miles Davis (现代爵士乐巨擘),磕药后就不会演奏...
Unless you can tell me miles,davis couldn't play stoned--
不磕药, 演奏得更好
he played better when he wasn'T.
我猜的, 没人能确定
I think--I mean,no one knows for sure.
我给 Leona 做总铁结合量以及,血清铁蛋白检查
I'll get leona a tibc and serum ferritin.
三分钟就可以检查出来了
We can test this in three minutes.
她是哪种人? Foreman?
So,what is she,foreman?
较白的黑人还是较黑的白人?
Light-skinned black chick or,dark-skinned white chick?
不能肯定, 再听一遍音乐会有提示么?
Not sure.,Can we hear the music again?
病情早期还看不到黄疸
it's too early to see jaundice from her liver.
没错, 这是Leona13岁时的照片
True--this is a photograph of,leona when she was 13 years old.
现在更黑了
She's darker now.
她在街上住了8个月
she's been living on,the streets for eight months.
没有晒过的痕迹,,除非她住的是条室内大街
No tan line,so unless those streets,she's been living on are indoor streets,
我认为她铁元素和黑色素沉积过多
I'm thinking she's got iron,deposits and melanin.
两者都是血色病的并发症,就和他外公一样
Both by-products of hemochromatosis,,just like granddad used to make.
超导量子干涉磁化仪可以,测量血液中的铁元素含量
Squid exam to calculate the,amount of iron in her blood.
注射排铁络合剂, 她中饭前就会好的
Then treat her with deferoxamine.,She'll be fine by lunch.
瞧, 我之前说错了,关于早饭前会好的
See,I was wrong before,,about the breakfast.
发现铁元素了, 很多很多
there's the iron.Lots of it.
我得不到这份工作了, 是吧?
I'm not going to get this job,am I?
早定了, 我第一眼看到你就决定了
It's a done deal.,I knew it the moment I saw you.
面试只是形式主义
Interview's just a formality.
House, 你在...
house.What are you--
这是Lisa Cuddy, 这是Patrick Linehan
lisa cuddy,this is patrick linehan.
Patrick是新的实习生, 轮转到我的部门
Patrick's going to be the new intern,rotating in my department.
我都不知道你在招人,很高兴见到你
I didn't even know you were looking for one.,Nice to meet you.
失礼了, 我紧张的时候就会笑
Sorry,I laugh when I'm nervous.
赌你这辈子一直都是这样的, 对吧?
Bet you've been doing that your whole life,,huh?
对哪个学科感兴趣, Patrick?
What kind of medicine are you interested in,,patrick?
癌症, 传染性疾病, 疑难杂症
Cancer,infectious disease.The big devils.
我觉得现在的医学过于机械化了
I think that medicine has become,too institutionalized.
应该传递给病人这样的信息,我们和他们一样
We need to send a message to our,patients that we're just like them.
我是说, 我们都是人
I mean,we're all people.
"我们都是人" 我喜欢
"We're all people."I like that.
她只认科学, 事实
She's all hard science,facts.
我喜欢了解他人的希望和梦想
I like to know a person's hopes and dreams.
你喜欢哪种音乐, Patrick?
What kind of music do you like,patrick?
-事实上, 我...,-我喜欢莫扎特
- Actually,I--,- I'm a mozart man.
他说出了我能感受, 但无法表达的
He says what I feel,but can't express.
我开会要迟到了
I'm late for a meeting.
看, 这就是面对面交谈为何如此重要
see,this is why the face-to-face,interview is so important.
得清楚你将和谁上床
You gotta know who you're,getting in bed with.
让他出去
Get him out of here.
排铁剂是一种螯合剂
Deferoxamine is a chelating agent.
和铁元素结合,就能从肝脏中分离出来了
It binds to the iron so that,her liver can get rid of it.
一旦铁元素分离出肝脏,最终会以尿液的形式排出体外
Once the iron's out of the liver,it's finally,evacuated by the body in the form of urine.
很快也没有痛苦
Should be quick and painless.
-Leona? 急救车,-怎么了?
- Leona? Crash cart.,- What's happening?
她无法呼吸了
She's not getting any air.
CT照片上她的肺就像瑞士奶酪
ct showed her lungs are swiss cheese.
呼吸器在起作用, 不过照这个趋势,她的时间所剩无几了
Ventilator's helping,but at this rate,,her time's basically up.
我们得出一个理论, 血色病
We developed a theory.Hemochromatosis.
如同称职的科学家,,我们测试并证明了这个理论
Like good scientists,we tested that theory.,We proved that theory.
在此基础上进行治疗
We acted based on that proof,and we treated her.
可结果却是, 她一脚踏进了鬼门关
As a result of which,she is on the verge of death.
是我的错?还是我们发现这科学方法中的缺陷?
Is it just me,or have we discovered,a flaw in the scientific method?
从头开始, 一步步考虑,,注射排铁剂时会怎样?
Walk me through it,step by step.What is,supposed to happen when you give someone deferoxamine?
这是种螯合剂
It's a chelating agent.
螯合剂如何起作用?
And what does the chelating do?
- 从肝脏中排出铁元素,- 怎么排出?
- Removes excess iron from the liver.--,- How?
铁很重, 会卡住,排铁剂就像是润滑剂
The iron is heavy.It gets stuck.,Deferoxamine is like a lubricant.
使铁润滑, 就能再次移动
It makes the iron slick so it,can move around again.
移动到哪?
Moves around where?
应该和排泄物一起泻出
It's supposed to be discharged through waste.
她的排泄系统情况有点糟糕
Her waste system is a little screwy right now.
铁没办法到它想去的地方
Means the iron can't go where it wants to go.
如果移动到肺部?
What if it moved to her lungs?
肺部有什么亲铁性物质,和铁结合, 开始在肺里穿洞
and whatever's in her lungs likes iron,,bound with it,started poking holes.
有哪些亲铁物质?
What likes iron?
氧和铁自动结合, 提高了感染的几率
Oxygen attaches itself to iron,,which increases her chance of infection.
不可能, 在放射之前我们,用了大量的抗生素
No,we started massive,antibiotics prior to the radiation.
一些神经退化类疾病亲和铁
Some neurodegenerative diseases like iron.
核磁共振成像没有发现脑部有铁沉积
Mri was clean.No iron deposits on the brain.
真菌也亲铁
Fungus likes iron.
没有反对意见?
No objections to that one?
如果是真菌感染, 那她死定了
if a fungus is doing all this,she's dead.
有25种抗真菌药,要是不知道是哪种真菌...
There are 25 antifungals.,If we don't know which fungus--
- 有疑问的时候, 扩展思维,- 最通常的是曲霉菌
- when in doubt,go broad.,- The most common is aspergillus.
继续用呼吸机
Continue to ventilate her lungs.
给她用伏立康唑滴液, 希望是曲霉菌吧
Get her on a voriconazole drip,and hope she has aspergillus.
过程是保密的, 你侵犯了他的隐私权,可你怎么能...
The process is confidential.,You violated his privacy.How did you even--
我在冷藏精子库里找 "失败者"
I looked up "loser" in the cryobank.
那个白痴周围100英里, 你都不想走近,却愿意和他生孩子
You wouldn't go within 100 miles of that idiot,,and yet you're willing to have his baby.
我不是想要约会, 我找累了...
I'm not looking for a date.,I'm tired of looking--
要棉球么?
Cotton ball?
你嫁给他我可不管
I don't care if you marry this guy,
和他约会, 检查他的垃圾,但你必须知道
date this guy,go through his garbage,,but you should know.
基因要紧, 找对人很重要
Genes matter.Who you are matters.
找个你信任的人吧
Find someone you trust.
和你相像的人?
Someone like you?
你喜欢的人
Someone you like.
听着, 哦, 我很抱歉, 好么
Listen.Uh,sorry.Okay.
- 不是你想的那样,- 我在帮他揉腿
- It's not what you think.--,- I rub his leg.
哦, Ingrid, 你好
Oh,ingrid.Hi.
好吧
Okay,
偷了他女友, 使你感到罪恶,我明白, 让我欣慰, 是件好事
you feel guilty about stealing the guy's girl.,I get that,and I'm glad.It's a good thing.
但你做了亲子鉴定
But you did the paternity test.
要么亲子鉴定呈不吻合,你可以在他面前挥舞结果
And either the paternity test comes back,negative,and you shove it in the guy's face,
要么鉴定吻合, 你闭上你的嘴,腿开始疼痛
or it comes back positive,and you shut up,,and your leg starts hurting.
要么我没进行测试
Or I never ran the test.
- 和你想的不一样,- Leona的肺衰竭了
- Not what you think.,- leona's lungs collapsed.
治疗没有作用, 猜错真菌了
The treatment's not working.,We've got the wrong fungus.
可以停下了, 被她破坏了
You can stop.She ruined it.
找对真菌有三条规则,地点, 地点, 地点
Three rules for hunting fungus.,Location,location,location.
Crandall 说她住在 Ridgeland 的,儿童庇护所里
Crandall says she was living at,the children's shelter in ridgeland.
可以确信她没有住在,Ridgeland 的儿童庇护所里
Okay,the one thing we know for sure is she was,not living at the children's shelter in ridgeland.
他为什么要撒谎?
Why would he lie about that?
他没有
he wouldn'T.
他相信乖女孩行动正确的故事
But he'd believe her story about the sweet,little girl trying to do the right thing.
我们没法问Leona住哪, 她喉咙插管
We can't ask leona where she was,,she's intubated.
别试着说话
Don't try to talk.
你嘴里有个很大的医疗器械
You've got a big medical thing in your mouth.
如果听懂了就眨眼
Just blink if you understand me.
很好
Fantastic.
如果你骗了Crandall 就眨眨眼
Blink if you lied to crandall about everything.
你在什么地方感染了真菌
You picked up a fungus somewhere.
如果照你跟新爸爸说的, 住在庇护所里
If you were living at the shelter,,like you told your new daddy,
我没什么办法了, 你会死的
then I got nothing to go on.And you will die.
好了, 你是不是骗了Crandall?
So,did you lie to crandall?
你的骗术根本不入流
You're a lousy con artist.
游戏的第一条原则是了解你的猎物
First rule of the game is know your mark.
在骗Crandall做爸爸的时候, 你成功了
Once you got crandall to bite,on the papa thing,you had him.
就算你说是基地组织人体炸弹成员
You could have told him that you were,servicing al-qaeda suicide bombers for crack,
他还是会让你挑选新房间的颜色
and this guy would still have let,you pick out the colors in your new room.
有没有骗Crandall?
Did you lie to crandall?
你在哪?
Where were you?
胜出的是...
And the winner is...
你来念, 我颁布时, 总是紧张
oh,you read it.,I just get so nervous at these things.
- 录音棚,- 她读过那本书了
- Recording studio.,- She read the book.
她知道Crandall多讨厌那个地方
She knew how much crandall,hated that place,what went on there.
她演得过火了
She overplayed her hand.
她很绝望, 如果不这么做,就仍陷在地狱
she was desperate.If she didn't sell this,,she was stuck in hell.
录音棚并不能在医学上帮我们什么
Recording studio doesn't help us medically.
录音棚
recording studios.
录音棚和其他房子有什么不同?
Why are these buildings different,from all other buildings?
隔音, 吸收声音, 也吸收湿气
Sound proofing.,Absorbs sound,also absorbs moisture.
那儿有湿气,很多的湿气...,Katirna 飓风带来的湿气...
Where there's moisture,,a lot of it--say,katrina moist--
按合菌病, 只在高度发霉的情况下有可能
zygomycosis.Only occurs at,the highest levels of mold.
开始静脉内注射两性霉素B,加入集落刺激因子
Start her on an iv drip of,amphotericin b with colony-stimulating factors.
她会好的, 在...
She'll be fine by...
晚饭之前
dinner.
她会好起来的
She's going to be fine.
她说她从没回去过那里
She said she'd never go back there.
她撒谎了
She lied to you.
她是你孩子, 习惯了就好
She's your kid.Get used to it.
谢谢你帮我注射
Thank you for the injections.
不客气
You're welcome.
你过来就是为了和我说这个?
You came all the way up here,just to tell me that?
不
No.
一切正常, 肝功能测试没有问题
pretty much normal.,Liver function tests are good.
谢谢, G-老兄
Thanks,g-man.
为什么觉得你能做个好父亲?
What makes you think you'd be a good father?
我不知道
I don't know.
感觉正确, 感觉不错
Feels right.Feels good.
好吧, 至少你有个不错的理由
Well,at least you've got a good reason.
感觉不错这个理由就足够了
Feels good is a good enough reason.
怎么了?
What's happening?
她窒息了, 她无法呼吸, 带他出去
She's choking.She can't breathe.,Get him out of here,will you?
出去
Out.
快, 拉上帘子
Quick,the curtain.
你在自行呼吸, 透不过气很正常
You're breathing on your own.,Choking's normal.
我骗了他
I lied to him.
我做了亲子鉴定
I ran a paternity test.
你的谎言
Your lie...
很烂
was a bad one.
他的确是你的父亲
He is your dad.
我们扯平了
We're even.
你的机器坏了, 连留言都没有
Uh,your machine's broken.,There's not even a message.
House, 你在吗?
House?Are you there?
好吧, 我想...星期一见,(亲子鉴定阴性)
Okay,see you monday,I guess.